# Miguel Rodríguez

# Designer and Developer

Madrid, Spain aphex95@gmail.com +34644518943 LinkedIn Github

#### **Profile**

Iterating towards tangible realities.

Transforming legacy projects into modern digital experiences. Working with UX/UI, Communication, Service, User-Centered Design and Front-End Development.

Thinking about the human-centered approach to design, collaborative work, and seamless digital products.

Currently Product Lead and Chief Creative Officer at Elite Training.

## Skills

Figma Ruby on Rails Sketch Bootstrap Adobe Tailwind CSS Keynote Wordpress InVision JavaScript Aaile Jquery **SCRUM** SQL OOP Lean UX ActiveRecord Shopify

HTML5 AJAX

CSS3 JSON

# Education

# Web Development Bootcamp Le Wagon

Madrid, Spain

Mauriu, Spairi

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

# **UX UI Full Time Bootcamp**

Ironhack

Madrid, Spain

Jan 2020 - Mar 2022

#### Communication Design Labs (Masters of Design and Innovation)

IED Madrid

Madrid, Spain

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

# Design with focus on Communication (User-centered design, service and interaction design)

Universidad de los Andes

Bogota, Colombia

2011 - 2018

#### Experience

#### Head of Product and CCO

#### Elite Training

Remote

Aug 2021 - Present

Innovation and revamp of the Communication, Marketing and Product departments in the company, through UX/UI Design, Design Thinking, Development with tools like Figma, Wordpress, Notion, Calendly, Slack.

# **UX UI Designer**

#### Filiatly

Madrid, Spain

Apr 2020 - Aug 2021

Full UX/UI design process and development of an Influencer Marketing SaaS platform.

- Wireframing, MidFi, HighFi and production design for desktop and mobile for the SaaS platform and landing website with Figma and Sketch.
- Design and development of online stores through Wordpress, Shopify, Prestashop, Squarespace and the technical integrations with the platform.

#### **Design Consultant**

# Elite Training

Remote

Jul 2019 - Jan 2020

As a Design Consultant, I am involved in the complete design process based on Agile, SCRUM and UX/UI methodologies as an exterior consultant and third-party provider to the company.

#### Main tasks:

- Design research of the companies' industry, history and processes origins.
- Identity reformulation and Corporate Branding, specifically Branding book re-design, branding colors, logo, fonts, copy and voice.
- Design Thinking tools focused on problem identification in every process (sales, customer service, accounting, IT.

#### Sales and Service Agent

# Concentrix

Bogotá, Colombia

Nov 2017 - Aug 2018

As a sales and customer service bilingual agent, I am involved in connecting with clients, offering products, and new information about their profiles, purchases and buying habits.

#### Main tasks:

- Salesforce management of sales of the Campaign Client (FLIR, LOREX) and of the profile of each end-user.
- Ticket creation and client's needs resolution and assistance.
- Direct connection with customers through chat and phone communication.

